Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
Mom! Mom! I've been chosen!
I'm an elite pilot, chosen to
protect all of mankind!
I'm the best in the world!
It's supposed to be a secret!
But I'll tell you anyway! Just for you!
Everyone will be nice to us from now on!
So, we won't be lonely anymore!
So, we'll be fine, even without Dad around!
We won't be lonely anymore!
So, look! Look at me!
Come on, Mom!
Synch rate, zero...
Not qualified to be the Second Child...
There's no reason for me to exist anymore.
Because no one will look at me now.
Not Dad, not Mom, not anyone.
There's no reason for me to live now.
Asuka Langley Sohryu, correct?
Intelligence Division 2 reports that they have
the Second Child safely in their custody.
I see.
It isn't like Division 2 to take seven days to
find her on top of losing her in the first place.
It's probably on purpose.
Maybe they're trying to spite us
here in the Tactical Division.
Possibly.
And today, Asuka's replacement,
the Fifth Child, arrives.
Everything is just too perfect.
Rei Ayanami...
So, that feeling I got really was her.
Like Mother...
Rei Ayanami and Mother...
What are you doing, Father?
Commander Ikari...
The cat died.
The one I'd left in my grandmother's care.
I hadn't paid any attention to her for so long,
but now, suddenly, I'll never see her again.
Why did you destroy the dummy system?
Not the dummy system,
what I destroyed was Rei.
I will only ask you this once. Why?
Because I am no longer happy,
even when you make love to me.
Why don't you just have your way
with my body?!
Like you did that time!
I'm disappointed in you.
Disappointed?!
You never hoped or expected anything
from me to begin with!
Nothing from me! Not anything! Nothing!
What am I supposed to do, Mother?
I wonder where Asuka is?
But what would be the point in seeing her?
Talk to her about Ayanami or something?
Everyone, including Toji and Kensuke,
lost their homes and left.
My friends...
I don't have anyone I can
call a friend anymore.
There's no one.
I can't go see Ayanami.
I don't have the courage for it.
I don't know how I'm supposed to face her.
Asuka, Miss Misato, Mother...
What should I...
What should I do?
Singing is great.
Singing enriches the soul.
It's the crowning achievement of the
civilization that the Lilim created.
Don't you feel the same?
Shinji Ikari?
My name...
Everyone knows your name.
I don't mean to be rude,
but I think you should be a little more
aware of your position.
You think so?
Who are you?
I'm Kaworu, Kaworu Nagisa.
One of the children that's part of
the design, just like you.
I'm the Fifth Child.
The Fifth Child?
You are? Nagisa?
You can just call me Kaworu, Ikari.
You can call me Shinji too.
It appears the Fifth Child has just arrived.
Kaworu Nagisa, his past records
have already been erased.
The same as Rei...
But the one thing we do know is that his
birthday coincides with the Second Impact.
The Committee sent him directly to us.
There's bound to be something to this.
In the Marduk Report, the matter of the Fifth
Child is also designated as confidential.
So, I did a little hacking into the
Intelligence Department's database.
You're so reckless!
It was worth it though.
I found out where Miss Ritsuko's being held.
How do you want to go about the
Fifth Child's synch test?
Let's hold off on the trick questions today
and get a straight reading
on what he's capable of.
Fixing graph depth.
Try lowering it another point three.
Yes, Sir.
Are these data readouts accurate?
All instrumentation is operating normally, Sir.
The Magi have not detected
any errors in the data, Sir.
Who would have expected that he would
synchronize with Unit 02
without the core being reconfigured?
This boy...
But this is beyond belief!
This should be impossible, given the system.
Nevertheless, these are the facts.
First, accept the facts for what they are,
and then investigate the why behind them.
Central Dogma is currently locked down.
Please use Route 22 as a detour.
You're the First Child, aren't you?
Rei Ayanami...
You're the same as me.
Who are you?
It seems the Fifth Child has
made contact with Rei.
I see.
The Magi are currently pouring
all their resources
into analyzing the data we got
from the Fifth Child.
And yet, we still have no idea what he is.
Who in the world is that boy?
Do not enter without permission.
I'll kill you if you come without asking!
Shinji still hasn't returned either.
I've failed as a guardian.
Central Dogma is currently open.
Please use Route 3 to transfer.
Hi, were you waiting for me?
No, not really. That's not what I was...
What are you doing today?
Well, the regular tests are over,
so all I have left is to take a shower
and go home, but...
But the truth is, lately, I don't
really want to go home.
A place to return to...
The fact that you have a home
will lead to your happiness.
It's a very good thing.
You think so?
I'd like to talk more with you.
May I come with you?
To take a shower. You still need
to go take one, right?
Is that a no?
Oh, no, that's not what I meant.
You go to such extremes to avoid first contact.
Are you afraid of connecting with other people?
If you don't get close to others,
you'll never be betrayed and
you'll never hurt each other.
But you'll also never be able
to forget your loneliness.
Humans can never banish
their loneliness for good,
because being human means being alone.
But humans are able to go on with their lives
because they're able to forget it every so often.
It's time.
Is it over already?
Yeah, we better go to bed.
Together?
Oh, no! I think there's probably
a room ready for you.
A separate one.
I see.
Humans constantly feel pain in their hearts.
Because the heart is so sensitive to pain,
humans also feel that to live is to suffer.
You're so delicate, like glass,
especially your heart.
Me?
Yes, you have my regard for it.
Regard?
It means, I love you.
EPISODE 24
THE
FINAL
MESSENGER
Nerv, the organization formed to be
Seele's executive branch...
It was created in order to put
our script into practice.
But now, it has become an organization
in the possession of one individual.
Precisely, we must take it back.
Before the promised day.
Nerv and the Eva series must be
in their true forms.
Ikari, you will bear the responsibility of
your malfeasance towards Seele.
The time that has been given to us runs short.
But the Lance of Longinus that stood
in the way of our desire is no more.
Soon, the final Angel will appear.
If we destroy it, our wish will come true.
Just a little longer, Yui.
Why am I here?
Why am I alive again?
For what?
And for whom?
The Fifth Child... That boy...
I feel as if he's the same as me.
Why?
I'm glad we're on the outskirts of the city,
because it kept you safe from all that.
But there's no guarantee that will be
the case next time.
So, the Horaki family will be taking care
of you starting tomorrow.
This will be goodbye for a while, Pen Pen.
Come on, I'll sleep on the floor.
It's okay.
You're the one who's doing me a favor
by letting me stay over.
I'm fine where I am.
What do you want to talk about?
There are things you want me to hear, right?
All sons of things have happened
since I came here.
Before coming here, I used
to live with my teacher.
The days were peaceful.
Nothing ever happened.
I only had to exist there.
But that was okay, because there
was nothing I had to do.
Did you hate people?
Not really, I think it didn't matter,
one way or another.
But I did hate my father.
Why am I telling Kaworu all this?
Maybe I was born, so that I would meet you.
How did it go? Did you get any data on him?
Here it is.
I borrowed it from First Lieutenant
Ibuki without her permission.
I'm sorry I keep making you do
these theft-like things.
What is this?!
It's no wonder Maya can't release
this information.
It's all theoretically impossible data.
You're right. It only deepens the mystery.
To think that he can freely set
his synch rate with the Eva...
And of his own will at that.
I guess this is yet again no time to be
worried about appearances.
I'm surprised you made it in.
There's something I want to ask you.
All conversations in here
are recorded, you know.
I don't care.
Just who is that boy? The Fifth Child?
He is likely the final messenger.
Come on, let's go.
Come with me, Adam's alter ego
and servant of the Lilim.
Eva Unit 02 is activating!
That's impossible! Where's Asuka?
In med room 303! It's been confirmed!
Then who in the world is...
It's unmanned! No entry plug
is present in Unit 02!
There's no one? It's not the Fifth Child?
A developing AT Field has been
detected in Central Dogma!
Is that Unit 02?!
No, its pattern is blue!
There's no doubt about it! It's an Angel!
What did you say?!
An Angel? That boy?
Target has passed through Level 4
and is still descending!
It's no good! We can't cut the power
to the linear carriage!
Target has passed through Level 5!
Emergency lockdown! Close all
partitions in Central Dogma!
Buy us some time, no matter how little.
Emergency lockdown, all Malebolge
levels being closed.
All personnel, evacuate.
I never imagined Seele would
send one directly to us.
The old men intend to step up
the schedule by forcing our hand.
The final Angel has entered Central Dogma
and is currently descending.
It's all going according to plan.
Ikari, you were a good friend,
a comrade who shared our aspirations,
and a collaborator who understood.
This is your final task.
I will be praying that it will be
accomplished by Unit 01.
Unit 02 is breaking through
the armored partitions!
Target has passed through Cocytus 2!
Send Eva Unit 01 after it.
Yes, Sir.
Stop it from invading Terminal Dogma
at all costs.
But why did the Angel take Unit 02?
Could it be planning to merge with Unit 02?
Or possibly to bring about destruction.
It's a lie! A lie! A lie!
That Kaworu is... He's an Angel?!
That's a lie!
It's a fact. Accept it.
Move out, understood?
Shinji's so late.
Eva Unit 01 heading down Route 2!
In pursuit of target!
You betrayed me! You betrayed my feelings!
You betrayed me, just like Father did!
Unit 01 has reached Level 4.
Coming into contact with the target!
There he is!
I've been waiting for you, Shinji.
Kaworu!
Asuka, sorry!
The Eva series.
Born from Adam, they are an abhorrent
existence for humans.
And the Lilim will even use them
in order to survive.
I can't understand.
Kaworu, stop this! Why?!
The Eva are made of the same body as I am.
Because I am born from Adam as well.
I could merge with them,
if only they didn't have souls.
Unit 02's soul has shut itself away for now.
An AT Field!
That's right. That's what you Lilim call it.
The sacred domain where none may trespass.
The light of the soul.
Lilim, you know, don't you?
That the AT Field is the wall that
everyone has in their heart?
I don't know anything about that, Kaworu!
Both Eva units have reached the lowest level.
Target distance to Terminal Dogma, 20.
If Unit 01's signal disappears
and another change occurs...
I know. We set this place to self-destruct, right?
It'll be better than letting them
set off the Third Impact.
I'm sorry.
It's okay, as long as I'm with you.
Thank you.
The fate of man...
The hope of man is written in sorrow.
What's going on?!
It's an AT Field of unprecedented power!
Light, electromagnetic, and particle waves!
It's blocking them all! We can't
monitor anything in there!
We're truly sealed off.
We've lost the target along with
Eva Unit 01 and Unit 02!
We can't contact the pilot!
Kaworu!
Wait!
The final safety has been released!
Heaven's Door is opening!
So, an Angel has finally reached it.
Hyuga...
What's that?!
What's the situation?
It's an AT Field!
The same kind of AT Field that we saw earlier
has developed near the barrier
around Terminal Dogma!
It's entering the barrier!
It can't be! Another Angel?!
It's no good! We can't confirm that!
Oh, no, it disappeared!
Disappeared?! The Angel did?!
Adam, our mother.
Must all who were born of Adam
return to Adam?
Even at the cost of destroying humanity?
No! This is...
Lilith?
I see, so that's what this is about, Lilim.
Thank you, Shinji.
I wanted you to stop Unit 02.
Otherwise, I may have gone on living with her.
Kaworu, why?
Because it's my destiny to continue to live
even if it may result in the
destruction of humanity.
But I can also die here.
Life and death are of equal value to me.
Dying of your own will, that is the one
and only absolute freedom there is.
What?
Kaworu, I don't understand what you're saying!
Kaworu...
My last will and testament.
Now, erase me from this world.
If you don't, you will be
the ones who are erased.
Only one life form will be chosen to survive
the time of destruction and be given a future.
And you are not a being who should die.
Your people need the future.
Thank you. I'm glad I met you.
Kaworu said that he loved me.
It was...
It was the first time someone
told me they loved me.
He was like me, and like Ayanami.
I loved him.
Kaworu was the one who should have survived.
He was a much better person than I am.
Kaworu should have been the one to survive.
You're wrong.
Only those who have the will to live
get to survive.
He wished to die.
He abandoned his will to live,
clinging instead to a false hope.
You did nothing wrong, Shinji.
You're cold, Miss Misato.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
Why do you pilot the Eva?
The final Angel is now gone,
What are you afraid of?
But Shinji is tormented.
"Because you're afraid."
"You are afraid."
And Misato and Asuka lay their hearts bare.
"It frightens you, doesn't it?"
"You want to be a good girl?"
"Why?"
All the while, going to others, seeking salvation.
"What is happiness?"
"Am I happy?"
Even as they accept that this is
one way for everything to end.
"Am I happy?"
What does she wish for?
And then...
The instrumentality of mankind begins.
Next time, "The World Ending"
The World Ending